44. What are carbon offsets? As the idea of global warming gains more acceptance in
the world, scientists are scrambling for a way to stop it before it's too late. One of
these ways is by using carbon offsets, also called carbon sharing. Carbon offsets were
designed to help countries comply with their obligations under the Kyoto Protocol. Under
the Kyoto Protocol, countries agree to reduce their carbon emissions by a certain percent.
Carbon emissions are measured in tons of carbon dioxide or other greenhouse gases. But because
these countries only have to reduce their total emissions, not every business or organization,
or even every country, has to reduce their emissions by the same amount. They just have
to reach the correct total reduction. Some countries, companies, and organizations can
reduce their carbon emissions more easily than others. Carbon offsets allow them to sell these
reductions to other entities that are moving more slowly. So a country or company can buy
carbon credits somewhere else. This prevents carbon from being emitted somewhere, but not by
that particular entity. Carbon offsets are controversial because they allow polluters to
avoid reducing their own carbon emissions. I won't turn off my tap. I'll pay someone else 10 pounds
to pay someone else 2 pounds to turn off their own tap, explain members of the environmental
group Rising Tide, which opposes carbon offsets. Others, however, say that carbon offsets are a
good way to reduce emissions overall while big countries figure out how to cut their own
emissions without hurting their economies. As the Kyoto Protocol is enforced and the world
becomes more serious about greenhouse gas reductions, carbon offset programs will become
widespread. Understanding this complex issue is very important if you want to stop global warming.
Keep researching and decide for yourself if selling carbon offsets will help or hurt us all.